<resources>

    <string name="app_name">SVARP</string>
    <string name="logo">appLog</string>

    <!--Languages-->
    <string name="lang_english">English</string>
    <string name="lang_hindi">हिंदी</string>
    <string name="lang_konkani">कोंकणी</string>
    <string name="lang_marathi">मराठी</string>
    <string name="lang_tamil">தமிழ்</string>
    <string name="lang_telugu">తెలుగు</string>
    <string name="lang_bengali">বাংলা</string>


    <!--OnBoarding Page-->
    <string name="onboarding_H1">Care &amp; Guidance When Needed</string>
    <string name="onboarding_T1">Get clear guidance at home. If needed, we’ll direct you to nearby health care — even without internet.</string>
    <string name="onboarding_H2">Talk or Type, Your Way</string>
    <string name="onboarding_T2">Speak or type in your own language. Use the app in the way that feels easiest for you.</string>
    <string name="onboarding_H3">Tell Us What You Feel</string>
    <string name="onboarding_T3">Choose what you are feeling and answer a few questions. We will guide you on what to do next.</string>

    <!--Headings-->
    <string name="heading"></string>
    <string name="heading1">Choose Language</string>
    <string name="heading2">How Can I Help?</string>
    <string name="heading3">Select Symptoms</string>
    <string name="heading4">Get Notification</string>
    <string name="heading5">Public Health Notice</string>
    <string name="heading6">Medical Disclaimer</string>
    <string name="heading7">Security Measures</string>
    <string name="heading8">Contact Us</string>
    <string name="heading9">Recommended Action</string>
    <string name="heading10">Symptoms You Mentioned</string>
    <string name="care">Care Guidance</string>
    <string name="assessment">Assessment</string>
    <string name="talk">Tap to Talk</string>
    <string name="term1">1. Acceptance of Terms</string>
    <string name="term2">2. Medical Disclaimer</string>
    <string name="term3">3. Data Privacy</string>
    <string name="term4">4. Changes to Terms</string>
    <string name="data_collection">Data Collection &amp; Usage</string>
    <string name="Setting">Setting</string>
    <string name="about">About SVARP</string>
    <string name="privacy">Privacy &amp; Disclaimer</string>
    <string name="privacy_policy">Privacy Policy</string>
    <string name="terms">Terms of Service</string>
    <string name="rate_us">Rate Us</string>
    <string name="help">24/7 Emergency Number</string>
    <string name="Tips">Daily Health Tips</string>
    <string name="tipTag">Stay Updated</string>
    <string name="subHeading">When to seek care</string>
    <string name="Symptoms_info">Symptoms Information</string>


    <!--Sub Titles-->
    <string name="advice">Call Ambulance</string>
    <string name="changeTime">Tap to change</string>
    <string name="sub_title">Reliable health guidance</string>
    <string name="sub_title1">Choose your preferred language for voice and text.</string>
    <string name="sub_title2">Tell us your symptoms for quick Assessment</string>
    <string name="sub_title3">Tap to choose your current symptoms</string>
    <string name="sub_title4">Get notified for Tips</string>
    <string name="condition1">By accessing and using SVARP, you accept and agree to be bound by the terms and provision of this agreement. In addition, when using these particular services, you shall be subject to any posted guidelines or rules applicable to such services.</string>
    <string name="condition2">The content provided in this app is for\ninformational purposes only and is not\nintended as a substitute for professional\nmedical advice, diagnosis, or treatment.\nAlways seek the advice of your\nphysician or other qualified health\nprovider with any questions you may\nhave regarding a medical condition.</string>
    <string name="condition3">Your use of the app is also governed by\nour Privacy Policy. Please review our\nPrivacy Policy to understand our\npractices regarding your personal\ninformation.</string>
    <string name="condition4">We reserve the right to modify these\nterms at any time. We will notify you of\nany changes by posting the new Terms\nof Service on this page.</string>

    <!--Buttons-->
    <string name="btnContinue">Continue (%d Selected)</string>
    <string name="check">Stop &amp; Analyze</string>
    <string name="btnNext">Next</string>
    <string name="btnSkip">Skip</string>
    <string name="btntalk">Start Voice Chat</string>
    <string name="btnStart">Get Started</string>
    <string name="btnCare">View Care Guidance</string>
    <string name="btnHome">Back to Home</string>

    <!--Descriptions-->
    <string name="back">back Button</string>
    <string name="icon">languageIcon</string>
    <string name="icon1">India Flag</string>
    <string name="icon2">right button</string>
    <string name="icon3">setting button</string>
    <string name="icon4">Select Symptom Icon</string>
    <string name="icon5">bell</string>
    <string name="icon6">reminder clock</string>
    <string name="icon7">Info</string>
    <string name="icon8">privacyIcon</string>
    <string name="icon9">iconDanger</string>
    <string name="icon10">iconCancel</string>
    <string name="icon11">iconMic</string>

    <!--Tags & Sentences-->
    <string name="appTag">
        Empowering you to take control of your health journey with simple, intuitive tools for monitoring and improvement.
    </string>
    <string name="tag">
        This application is for informational purposes only. It does not provide medical advice, diagnosis, or treatment.
        Always seek the advice of your physician or other qualified health provider with any questions you may have
        regarding a medical condition.
    </string>
    <string name="tag1">Adding your symptoms helps AI give more accurate results.</string>
    <string name="tag2">Analysis works entirely on-device</string>
    <string name="tag3">Select what you are feeling</string>
    <string name="tag4">
        We are committed to protecting your personal health information. This policy outlines how we collect, use,
        and safeguard your data in accordance with HIPAA and GDPR regulations.
    </string>
    <string name="data_collection_intro">
        We collect information to provide better healthcare insights. This includes:
    </string>
    <string name="tag5">
        Your data is encrypted both in transit and at rest using industry-standard protocols. We utilize multi-factor
        authentication and strict access controls to ensure your information remains private.
    </string>
    <string name="tag6">
        If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at privacy@SVARP.
    </string>
    <string name="data_collection_list">
        • Personal identification information (Name, DOB)\n
        • Health metrics and assessment results\n
        • Usage data and device information
    </string>


    <!--miscellaneous-->
    <string name="version">Version 2.4.0</string>
    <string name="rights">© 2026 SVARP Inc. All rights reserved.</string>
    <string name="reminder_enabled">Reminder Enabled</string>
    <string name="reminder_disabled">Reminder Disabled</string>
    <string name="back_exit">Press back again to exit</string>

    <string-array name="health_notices">
        <item>Staying hydrated helps reduce headache and fatigue. Aim for 8 glasses of water daily.</item>
        <item>Getting 7–9 hours of sleep each night helps your immune system stay strong.</item>
        <item>A 10-minute walk can improve your mood and reduce stress significantly.</item>
        <item>Eating a variety of colourful fruits and vegetables provides essential vitamins.</item>
        <item>Washing hands for at least 20 seconds prevents the spread of most infections.</item>
        <item>Deep breathing for 5 minutes can lower your heart rate and reduce anxiety.</item>
        <item>Limiting screen time before bed improves sleep quality and reduces eye strain.</item>
        <item>Regular meals maintain stable blood sugar and help you stay energised all day.</item>
        <item>Sunlight exposure for 15–20 minutes daily supports healthy vitamin D levels.</item>
        <item>Stretching for a few minutes after waking up reduces muscle stiffness.</item>
        <item>Reducing added sugar intake lowers your risk of diabetes and heart disease.</item>
        <item>Spending time outdoors in nature has proven benefits for mental wellbeing.</item>
        <item>Listening to music you enjoy can reduce cortisol — your body\'s stress hormone.</item>
        <item>Keeping a symptom journal helps you spot patterns and share them with your doctor.</item>
        <item>Laughing genuinely boosts your immune system and relieves physical tension.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="urgent_prefix">⚠️ URGENT: </string>
    <string name="assessment_prefix">Assessment: </string>

    <string-array name="symptom_display_list">
        <item>Fever</item>
        <item>Cough</item>
        <item>Headache</item>
        <item>Fatigue</item>
        <item>Sore Throat</item>
        <item>Vomiting</item>
        <item>Body Ache</item>
        <item>Dizziness</item>
        <item>Skin Rash</item>
        <item>Eye Discomfort</item>
        <item>Toothache</item>
        <item>Chest Pain</item>
        <item>Shortness of Breath</item>
        <item>Nausea</item>
        <item>Weakness</item>
        <item>Weight Loss</item>
        <item>Blood in Stool</item>
        <item>Blood in Urine</item>
        <item>Diarrhea</item>
        <item>Stomach Ache</item>
    </string-array>

    <!--Symptom Info-->
    <string name="info_fever">🌡️ Fever\nA fever is your body\'s natural defence mechanism — it raises your temperature to make it harder for viruses and bacteria to survive. A mild fever (up to 38.5°C) is usually safe to manage at home with rest and fluids. If it goes above 39.5°C, lasts more than 3 days, or comes with a stiff neck or rash, see a doctor promptly.</string>
    <string name="info_cough">🫁 Cough\nA cough is your airway\'s way of clearing out irritants, mucus, or infection. A dry cough is often caused by viral infections or allergies, while a wet cough with phlegm usually points to a chest infection. Most coughs resolve within 2 weeks. If you\'re coughing up blood, or it\'s been going on for more than 3 weeks, get it checked.</string>
    <string name="info_headache">🧠 Headache\nHeadaches are one of the most common symptoms and are usually harmless. Tension headaches feel like a tight band around the head and are often caused by stress, poor posture, or screen time. Dehydration is a surprisingly common trigger — drinking water often helps quickly. Migraines are more intense, often one-sided, and may come with nausea or light sensitivity. A sudden severe headache unlike any before warrants immediate medical attention.</string>
    <string name="info_fatigue">😴 Fatigue\nFatigue is more than just feeling tired — it\'s a persistent lack of energy that doesn\'t fully go away with rest. It can be caused by poor sleep, anaemia, thyroid issues, viral infections, or even stress and anxiety. Short-term fatigue during an illness is normal. If it\'s been going on for more than 2 weeks without a clear reason, a simple blood test can often find the cause.</string>
    <string name="info_sore_throat">🗣️ Sore Throat\nA sore throat is most commonly caused by a viral infection like the common cold, which means antibiotics won\'t help. It usually gets better on its own within 5–7 days. Warm salt water gargles, honey in warm tea, and staying hydrated can speed up recovery. If your throat is very swollen, you have white patches, or you\'re struggling to swallow, it could be a bacterial infection — worth seeing a doctor.</string>
    <string name="info_vomiting">🤢 Vomiting\nVomiting is usually triggered by a stomach virus, food poisoning, or motion sickness and tends to resolve within 24 hours. The biggest risk with vomiting is dehydration — sipping small amounts of ORS or clear fluids regularly is the most important thing you can do. Avoid solid food until the vomiting settles, then ease back in with bland foods like rice or toast. If vomiting continues beyond 24 hours or there\'s blood, seek medical attention.</string>
    <string name="info_body_ache">💪 Body Ache\nBody aches during an illness happen because your immune system releases chemicals called cytokines that cause inflammation throughout the body — this is actually a sign your body is fighting back. Rest, warm baths, staying hydrated, and paracetamol can help ease the discomfort. Body aches that persist long after an illness or that are very severe in specific joints may need further investigation.</string>
    <string name="info_dizziness">💫 Dizziness\nDizziness is often caused by something simple — dehydration, getting up too quickly, low blood sugar, or tiredness. Sitting or lying down, drinking water, and having a light snack usually helps within minutes. If dizziness is severe, comes with chest pain, difficulty speaking, or loss of balance, it could signal something more serious and needs immediate attention.</string>
    <string name="info_skin_rash">🔴 Skin Rash\nRashes have many causes — allergic reactions, heat, viral infections, or skin conditions like eczema. Most mild rashes are itchy but harmless and resolve within a few days with cool compresses and calamine lotion. Avoid scratching as it can break the skin and cause infection. A rash that spreads rapidly, comes with fever, or looks like tiny blood spots under the skin needs urgent medical evaluation.</string>
    <string name="info_eye_discomfort">👁️ Eye Discomfort\nEye discomfort is most commonly caused by digital eye strain from prolonged screen use — symptoms include dryness, burning, and blurred vision. The 20-20-20 rule helps: every 20 minutes, look at something 20 feet away for 20 seconds. Lubricating eye drops can relieve dryness. If the eye is red, producing discharge, very painful, or your vision has changed, see a doctor promptly.</string>
    <string name="info_toothache">🦷 Toothache\nToothache is usually caused by tooth decay, a cracked tooth, an abscess, or gum disease. Warm salt water rinses can reduce inflammation, and paracetamol can manage pain temporarily — but these are not cures. A dental infection left untreated can spread, so it\'s important to see a dentist within a couple of days rather than hoping it goes away.</string>
    <string name="info_chest_pain">❤️ Chest Pain\nChest pain always deserves attention. While it can be caused by something benign like acid reflux, muscle strain, or anxiety, it can also signal heart or lung problems. Pain that is crushing, spreading to the arm or jaw, or comes with sweating and breathlessness needs emergency attention — call 102/108 immediately. Even if you suspect it\'s minor, chest pain you can\'t explain should be evaluated by a doctor the same day.</string>
    <string name="info_shortness_of_breath">🌬️ Shortness of Breath\nFeeling short of breath can be caused by a range of things — from anxiety and asthma to more serious conditions like heart failure. Mild breathlessness after exertion is normal, but breathlessness at rest, worsening over time, or accompanied by chest pain or bluish lips is a medical emergency. If you\'re unsure, it\'s always safer to get checked than to wait.</string>
    <string name="info_nausea">😮 Nausea\nNausea is that uncomfortable urge to vomit — it can come from motion sickness, food, stress, medication, or a stomach bug. Ginger tea, small bland meals, and staying upright after eating can help. Sipping fluids slowly is better than gulping. If nausea is persistent, comes with severe abdominal pain, or you can\'t keep any fluids down for more than 24 hours, see a doctor.</string>
    <string name="info_weakness">🔋 Weakness\nA general feeling of weakness is common during illness as your body diverts energy to fighting infection. It can also be caused by anaemia, low blood sugar, dehydration, or thyroid problems. Eating a balanced meal, staying hydrated, and resting usually helps. Sudden severe weakness in one side of the body, face, or limbs needs emergency attention as it can be a sign of stroke.</string>
    <string name="info_weight_loss">⚖️ Unexplained Weight Loss\nLosing weight without trying — especially more than 4–5 kg over a few months — is something your body is trying to tell you. It can be caused by thyroid overactivity, diabetes, chronic infection, or digestive conditions. It\'s rarely something to panic about, but it always warrants investigation. A blood test and a visit to your doctor can usually point in the right direction quickly.</string>
    <string name="info_blood_in_stool">🩸 Blood in Stool\nBlood in the stool can appear bright red (usually from the lower digestive tract — like haemorrhoids) or dark and tarry (indicating bleeding higher up in the gut). Either way, it should always be evaluated by a doctor — even if you feel fine otherwise. Many causes are benign and treatable, but some require prompt investigation. Don\'t ignore it or self-medicate.</string>
    <string name="info_blood_in_urine">🩺 Blood in Urine\nBlood in urine — whether you can see it or it\'s detected on a test — is not something to dismiss. Common causes include urinary tract infections, kidney stones, or bladder irritation. Drink plenty of water and see a doctor the same day. You\'ll usually need a urine test and possibly an ultrasound to find the cause.</string>
    <string name="info_diarrhea">🚽 Diarrhea\nDiarrhea is the body\'s rapid way of expelling irritants. Most cases resolve within 2 days with proper hydration. ORS is the most effective way to replace lost fluids and salts — plain water alone isn\'t enough. Stick to bland foods: bananas, rice, toast. Avoid dairy, fatty, and spicy food. If diarrhea contains blood, or lasts beyond 3 days, see a doctor.</string>
    <string name="info_stomach_ache"> Stomach Ache\nStomach pain is extremely common — indigestion, gas, constipation, a stomach bug, period cramps, or stress can all cause it. A warm compress and herbal tea can help with mild cramps. Avoid heavy, spicy, or oily food until it settles. Pain that is severe, comes on suddenly, is focused in the lower right (appendix area), or doesn\'t improve within a few hours should be seen by a doctor.</string>
    <string name="symptoms_fallback">Monitor your symptoms and consult a healthcare professional if they persist.</string>

    <string name="sympInfo">About this symptom</string>
    <string name="risk_safe">Safe</string>
    <string name="risk_moderate">Moderate Risk</string>
    <string name="risk_danger">Danger</string>
    <string name="listening">I\'m listening</string>
    <string name="condition_prefix">Condition: </string>
    <string name="advice_prefix">Advice: </string>

</resources>
